in this code we have
an array pets that contains four
different types of pets
and a second array my pets which
contains
two elements from the pet's array fish
and lizard this problem asks us to
remove lizard from my pets
and then print the value of my pets to
match the expected output
ruby provides us a convenient method to
remove the last element of an array
let's use p to output my pets
you see that this array has two elements
and lizard
which is the element we want to remove
is the last element
the array pop method removes
and returns the last element of an array
so we'll call pop on the my pets array
and let's output my pets again because
pop is a destructive method
we now expect to see an array with only
one element
fish and that's what we see
so we've successfully removed lizard
from the my pets array
and now we want to print the value of my
pets to match the expected output
you may think that since my pets now
references an array with only one
element
we don't need to worry about element
reference
but when we run our code you can see
that that's not the case
we still need to reference which element
we want to access
in this case our array has only one
element
so we know that we can access it at
index 0.
running our code again we see the
expected output
you